<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tajdid Rahman</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 18:14:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Competitor Research</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I and my teammates will be conducting our own individual research into competitor websites for our client. Mark Boulton said that research is vital to the success of any design solution and I totally agree with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;indeedhttpindeedcouk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://indeed.co.uk&quot;&gt;Indeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/indeed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Indeed&quot; title=&quot;Indeed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed is a job search engine website, clearly demonstrating their focus is on delivering the best search results to users no matter where they are. The site is similar to Google in terms of opting for functionality over visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design uses a lot of negative space, thus keep it clear and simple. The main colour of the website is blue, which, in colour psychology, is perceived to be a calm, soothing colour making the user feel relaxed. Even Mark Boulton states that a design which mostly consists of blue could be described as ‘cold’, ‘calm’ or ‘reserved’. Blue is also commonly associated with a lot of businesses such as Intel, Twitter, Samsung, Tesco, etc. Indeed also uses orange for highlighting certain words, for example when a job is available a text will show up stating a new job is available. This text is coloured orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site doesn’t seem to use a strict grid system as the top navigation and the footer are full width, whereas the main body is constrained within a container which stays in the centre of the browser window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of typography, the site uses Arial, a san-serif font, as their primary typeface. This suits a website such as Indeed, as it easier to read on screen and allows the users to read the information much more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-experience&quot;&gt;User experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed aggregates job postings from thousands of sources and posts them on one site. Instead of visiting five or six different online job sites, Indeed brings the power of many into the power of one. This saves you lots of time in your job search. When you apply to a job on Indeed, you will most likely be redirected to another search site to apply. This can be slightly irritating, but it’s worth it for the efficiency gains from only having to search one job site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Indeed don’t use responsive web design, but they do provide their job search engine product as a dedicated iPhone, iPad, and Android app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monsterhttpwwwmonstercouk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monster.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Monster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/monster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monster&quot; title=&quot;Monster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monster is a clean job search website, which keeps the search results neat - at first you only get the job title, company, location, and date when last updated, which is just what you need. Everything else about the purple-white UI, from the straightforward search window to the clean and easy-to-browse favourites, looks aesthetically pleasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-1&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Indeed, Monster seems to try and fill up most of the space of the website with content, all though the website still looks good. The primary colour of the site is purple, which is usually associated with royalty, wealth and money. I personally think this is an unusual colour scheme for a job board site even though in colour psychology it fits with the theme of the site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site has a fixed width of 994 pixels and is centred horizontally within the browser window. It doesn’t seem to use a strict grid system, but in some places it organised in columns, for example near the footer at the bottom there are 4 columns containing links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of typography, the site uses a san-serif font, most likely Arial. The site also has a distinguished type hierarchy, for example content links are coloured blue, headings are bold and black and links in the header a white with underlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-experience-1&quot;&gt;User Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monster offers useful, content-rich career resources to manage the job search and application process from start to finish. You can effortlessly shortlist favourite jobs and keep track of them, both within the app and through email alerts. The site can also retrieve a maximum of 250 job listings at a time, giving you plenty of options to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ni-job-finderhttpwwwnijobfindercouk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nijobfinder.co.uk/&quot;&gt;NI Job Finder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/nijobfinder.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NI Job Finder&quot; title=&quot;NI Job Finder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NI Job Finder is Northern Ireland’s local job search engine. The sites search capability is simple, then lets you make it as detailed as you want. It provided complete control of the filter options. Date, relevance to keywords, company, education, and experience are just some of your options to generate a very targeted job search with the most relevant listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-2&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the other two job boards, NI Job Finders seems to pack a lot of information onto their homepage. You have the search engine at the very top of the site, with an image on right side which adds a bit more colour to the site. The primary colour of the website is turquoise, which is also the main colour of the logo. The turquoise colour is also used as the background colour for the search engine and some headings. The website, Bourn Creative, said;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The color turquoise is associated with meanings of refreshing, feminine, calming, sophisticated, energy, wisdom, serenity, wholeness, creativity, emotional balance, good luck, spiritual grounding, friendship, love, joy, tranquility, patience, intuition, and loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The websites typography is very simple and uses a san-serif font. Again, san-serif fonts suit these types of websites as it is very modern and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website seems to use some of sort of grid system, although it doesn’t seem that strict. There is too much information on the site, which can confuse the user and could lead them to leave the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;user-experience-2&quot;&gt;User Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mention before, the job search experience is quite user friendly. I was able to search jobs using various filters, thus allowing me to accurately find the right job for me. The amount of content on the homepage can be overwhelming for some people, but it doesn’t really affect the user experience too much. Unfortunately the website does respond to mobile devices and it does seem to have any kind of mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boulton, M. (2014). Chapter 6, The Design Process. Designingfortheweb.co.uk. Retrieved 5 November 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part2/part2_chapter6.php&quot;&gt;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part2/part2_chapter6.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bourn, J. (2010). Meaning of The Color Turquoise. Retrieved 5 November 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bourncreative.com/meaning-of-the-color-turquoise/&quot;&gt;http://www.bourncreative.com/meaning-of-the-color-turquoise/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/11/06/competitor-research/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/11/06/competitor-research/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Composition in Web Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Composition is about how ideas and design elements are laid out into a whole, composing a design. It is arguably the most important part of a design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good composition will boost the user experience when navigating through a website and will help create a better design overall. When creating composition, the designer should aim for alignment, consistency and strong unity. Composition also helps to add visual relevance to layouts so that it can help users to understand more about their journey on a website, where they should head next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/gomedia_composition_girl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Composition&quot; title=&quot;Composition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A layout is the basis of a website. It brings different aspects of design into play and guides the user through each section and tells them what is most important. With different browser types, screen resolutions and sizes a designer needs to know what layout to use whether it is fixed, fluid or responsive. In this post I will talk about different aspects of layout used in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rule-of-thirds&quot;&gt;Rule of Thirds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was first made aware of the rule of thirds whilst working on my final GCSE art project. At first I didn’t think much of it, but once I saw it in practice I was simply amazed how it transformed the way I viewed art. The rules of thirds is commonly associated with art and photography, but it can also be applied to web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rule of thirds is a essentially a guideline that is used when creating designs, photographs, films and paintings. The rule of thirds uses a grid of 3x3, hence the name, which can placed on any design, photography and painting which can help the user to alter their work to make them more appealing to the viewer or audience. It is used to help balance designs and work and make them more interesting and eye catching to the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/ruleofthirds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rule of Thirds&quot; title=&quot;Rule of Thirds&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grid-systems&quot;&gt;Grid Systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I’m working on website I use a grid system as they are crucial to good web design. Whether I’m using my own prebuilt, responsive, CSS-based grid system or designing around guides in Photoshop, grids provide structure and clarity to web design. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grids have been used for centuries in print design. They have helped rein in the chaos of the web as well—time was, web pages were built with lots of nested tables and spacer gifs. This was not the best solution, but once CSS became more popular and supported, designers were quick to use grids in their designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“When you add complexity, you can decrease usability and there is a danger the grid would become so complex the designer can’t use it.”&lt;/em&gt; - Mark Boulton (Designing for the Web, Chapter 5, Part 23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;golden-ratio&quot;&gt;Golden Ratio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Golden Ratio is a beautifully simple piece of mathematical theory that can help make your designs feel well proportioned and pleasing on the eye.”&lt;/em&gt; - Sam Hampton-Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/g-ratio.png&quot; alt=&quot;Golden Ratio&quot; title=&quot;Golden Ratio&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Figure. Image found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativebloq.com/design/designers-guide-golden-ratio-12121546&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Golden Ratio is a grid system that helps designers/developers plan their websites or designs to help improve user satisfaction or appear more aesthetically pleasing to the human eye. The ratio does not strictly have to be similar to figure X above, it can be adapted. Twitter (as shown in figure X below) have flipped it to fit for their design and information to make it look better and easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/gr-twitter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter Golden Ration&quot; title=&quot;Twitter Golden Ratio&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Figure. Image found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativebloq.com/design/designers-guide-golden-ratio-12121546&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boultan, M. (2014). Chapter 23, Grid Systems. Designingfortheweb.co.uk. Retrieved 22 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part5/part5_chapter23.php&quot;&gt;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part5/part5_chapter23.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hampton-Smith, S. (2014). The designer’s guide to grid theory. Creativebloq.com. Retrieved 22 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativebloq.com/web-design/grid-theory-41411345&quot;&gt;http://www.creativebloq.com/web-design/grid-theory-41411345&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stayrook, J. (2014). Design to the nines and the rule of thirds. Webdesigner Depot. Retrieved 22 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2014/01/design-to-the-nines-and-the-rule-of-thirds/&quot;&gt;http://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2014/01/design-to-the-nines-and-the-rule-of-thirds/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2013/08/29/innovative-appraoches-web-layout/&quot;&gt;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2013/08/29/innovative-appraoches-web-layout/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativebloq.com/design/designers-guide-golden-ratio-12121546&quot;&gt;http://www.creativebloq.com/design/designers-guide-golden-ratio-12121546&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coolen, J. (2009). 7 Key Principles That Make A Web Design Look Good - noupe. noupe. Retrieved 3 November 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noupe.com/design/7-key-principles-that-make-a-web-design-look-good.html&quot;&gt;http://www.noupe.com/design/7-key-principles-that-make-a-web-design-look-good.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/10/16/composition-in-web-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/10/16/composition-in-web-design/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recieved feedback on my blog from Clair Stevenson in the form of an audio file, which you can have a listen to below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ####Feedback --&gt;
&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source src=&quot;/projectblog/downloads/blog_audio_feedback_01.m4a&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with all that has been said about my blog. The work on this blog is not up to my usual standards and that is largely due to the lack of motivation and not treating my blog like an assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve now updated my blog with the &lt;a href=&quot;/projectblog/minutes/&quot;&gt;minutes&lt;/a&gt; and a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;/projectblog/downloads/Terms_of_Reference_Final.docx&quot;&gt;terms of reference&lt;/a&gt; and I am currently writing up an update on colours and typography in web design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/10/12/blog-feedback/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/10/12/blog-feedback/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ToR Feedback and More</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we received feedback on our Terms of Reference that we created for our client. The feedback was mostly positive and we received a very high mark for our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what &lt;em&gt;Clair Stevenson&lt;/em&gt;, our tutor, wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A design and technical challenge has been accepted by the team and by the live client with serious money by way of Wordpress templates being used. Careful planning considerations have already taken place with wireframes. Have adequate communication links been established between the team and client?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is true that we are falling short on communication between each other, but we’ll hopefully change this by incorporating team managment tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the Terms of Reference by &lt;a href=&quot;/projectblog/downloads/Terms_of_Reference_Final.docx&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;role-changes&quot;&gt;Role Changes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the team lead role has been passed on to &lt;em&gt;Lauren McKimm&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/10/07/terms-of-reference-feedback/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/10/07/terms-of-reference-feedback/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Typography in Web Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Typography has an important role to play in helping convey information. The amount of typefaces available are few and far between, and with the introduction of web font services such as Typekit and Google Web Fonts the available fonts to the web has become easier than ever to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A popular combination is to use serif fonts as the body of text and sans-serif fonts for the headings or vice-
versa. The body text should be easily readable with the heading fonts complementary and potentially playful. A general rule is to use no more than 2/3 typefaces on a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hierarchy&quot;&gt;Hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a strong typography hierarchy is vital in all mediums of graphic design. It’s a system used for organising type that allows a designer to establish an order of importance, thus allowing the user to easily view the information they’re looking for and navigate the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways of accomplishing typography hierarchy is by varying the type size to differentiate content. Although colour and layout is important, different type sizes, spread across a website, will speak louder to readers the importance of a pages elements. It also helps readers in a hurry to quickly pick out the important parts - which could also lead to the reader staying longer and reading on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/images/weight_diagram_b.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Chapter 13, Hierarchy, Solving the design problem (Boulton, 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 represents the relationship between Times New Roman’s uppercase and lowercase typefaces and its weights. This is also known as a type family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“if a designer has set type in roman and they need to add emphasis to a certain point in the copy, they would follow the lines to any on the second lines – bold lower case, small caps, full caps, and italic lower case or sloped small caps. If they were to jump to, say, bold italic lower case, or a more extreme example, bold sloped caps, the effect would be horrible. If the designer is setting type in bold lower case they could go on to add bold caps, or bold italic lower case without much bother. ” - &lt;em&gt;Chapter 13, Hierarchy, Solving the design problem (Boulton, 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above quote suggests that hierarchy can also be achieved by not only using different sizes of type to achieve it, but we can also use different styles; for example, all-caps, or using italic for sub-headings. As I mentioned before, serif and sans-serif typefaces can also be mixed to good effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;swiss-style&quot;&gt;Swiss Style&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a big fan of the swiss style, so I had to discuss the topic in my blog. The famous swiss style is often referred to as the International Typegraphic Style or just simply International Style. The style was formed in Switzerland back in the mid 1900s and was the basis of modern graphic design in the mid 20th century and remains so today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term International Typographic Style came around due to the aim of the style, which is to be clean and improve readability in design, but the characteristics of the style also composes of sans-serif typefaces, asymmetrical layouts, grid systems and visual communication using photography with type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c3.staticflickr.com/3/2026/3530252783_cec577fd01_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photography by insect54&quot; title=&quot;Publicité et arts graphiques / advertising and graphic art&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Photography by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/insect54/3530252783/in/set-72157614426991414/&quot;&gt;insect54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Perfection is achieved, not when there is nothing left to add, but when there is nothing left to remove.”
- &lt;em&gt;Antoine de Saint-Exupéry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designishistory.com/1940/joseph-mueller-brockmann/&quot;&gt;Josef Müller-Brockmann&lt;/a&gt; was a leading pioneer of the Swiss style and was the founder and editor of the Zurich published journal Neue Grafik, who introduced the Swiss Style into America. He concerned himself with functional and objective design that by restricting design elements in the confine of a typographic grid, would shift the focus of image on the core message displayed by a clean and simple geometrical aesthetic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other assoicated artists of Swiss design include the likes of;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armin_Hofmann&quot;&gt;Armin Hofmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Bill&quot;&gt;Max Bill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lohse.ch/bio_e.html&quot;&gt;Richard Paul Lohse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designishistory.com/1940/emil-ruder/&quot;&gt;Emil Ruder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;swiss-style-in-web-design&quot;&gt;Swiss Style in Web Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Swiss Style is devoted to the minimal elements of design such as typography and content rather than textures and illustrations. The impact of these styles on the web is that they are naturally very user-friendly interfaces, as any message is conveyed clearly, with minimal artistic clutter around it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boulton, M. (2014). Chapter 13, Hierarchy. Designingfortheweb.co.uk. Retrieved 30 September 2014,&lt;br /&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part3/part3_chapter13.php&quot;&gt;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part3/part3_chapter13.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flask, D. (2014). Swiss Design : Design Is History. Designishistory.com. Retrieved 15 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designishistory.com/home/swiss/&quot;&gt;http://www.designishistory.com/home/swiss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terror, D. (2009). Lessons From Swiss Style Graphic Design - Smashing Magazine. Smashing Magazine. Retrieved 15 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2009/07/17/lessons-from-swiss-style-graphic-design/&quot;&gt;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2009/07/17/lessons-from-swiss-style-graphic-design/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- http://ilovetypography.com/2008/02/28/a-guide-to-web-typography/ --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/30/typography-in-web-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/30/typography-in-web-design/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colours in Web Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Colours play an important role in all design mediums. Although the visual functionality of a website is influenced primarily by the text on the screen and page layout, colour takes it a step further by making a psychological impact (Irby, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Boulton reports that designing with colour in graphic design is the most difficult to get right (Boulton, 2014). I completely agree with this statement  as colour is very subjective. Some like a combination of green and blue, whereas some find it boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right colours when designing a website is something that requires a lot of patience, experimentation and guesswork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People make a subconscious judgment about a product in less than 90 seconds of viewing, and a majority of these people base that assessment on color alone. In fact, almost 85% of consumers cite color as the primary reason they buy a particular product, and 80% of people believe color increases brand recognition. (Gillett, 2014)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any professional web designer would be able to tell you that there are three properties to colour - hue, saturation and value;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hue&lt;/strong&gt; - what part of the spectrum the colour belongs to (such as red, yellow, pink, green, purple, orange or blue).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturation&lt;/strong&gt; - how rich a hue is; neon colours, for example, are very saturated, whilst pastel ones are less so.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value&lt;/strong&gt; - how bright a color is; really, it is looking at how close it is to white or black.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The property that many people mistakenly use is the hue, as they tend to choose colors that clash together instead of flowing nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projectblog/img/posts/colourwheel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Colour Wheel&quot; title=&quot;Colour Wheel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Colour wheel image found &lt;a href=&quot;http://barbiemutation.blogspot.co.uk/2013/04/color-wheel-madness.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just take a look at the colour wheel (figure 1) here. It looks nice and the colours flow perfectly into one another — so it goes without saying that visually, blue, and the colours to the left and right of it, blend nicely together. They’re called analogous colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irby, L. (2014). Choosing Colors For Your Website Design. 2createawebsite.com. Retrieved 25 September 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.2createawebsite.com/design/color-psychology.html&quot;&gt;http://www.2createawebsite.com/design/color-psychology.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gillett, R. (2014). What Your Logo’s Color Says About Your Company (Infographic). Fast Company. Retrieved 12 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3028378/leadership-now/what-your-logos-color-says-about-your-company-infographic&quot;&gt;http://www.fastcompany.com/3028378/leadership-now/what-your-logos-color-says-about-your-company-infographic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boulton, M. (2014). Chapter 15, Printing the Web. Designingfortheweb.co.uk. Retrieved 16 October 2014, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part4/part4_intro.php&quot;&gt;http://designingfortheweb.co.uk/part4/part4_intro.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/25/colours-in-web-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/25/colours-in-web-design/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting the Client</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Enim recusandae aliquam rerum sequi esse unde ratione praesentium, numquam, delectus est id distinctio aut labore eligendi quisquam inventore hic laboriosam reiciendis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://unsplash.imgix.net/reserve/m6rT4MYFQ7CT8j9m2AEC_JakeGivens%20-%20Sunset%20in%20the%20Park.JPG?q=75&amp;amp;w=1080&amp;amp;h=1080&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;s=6365b53b83834a1c4b12e307c0c48145&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; title=&quot;Title&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Blanditiis ipsa id dolorum hic omnis, incidunt exercitationem itaque aspernatur assumenda neque ipsam architecto nobis dolorem officiis voluptate rem, magni nostrum optio?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/16/meeting-the-client/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/16/meeting-the-client/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding a Client</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today as group we discussed about finding a client that would be willing to allow us to create a website for them. Alec mentioned that he may have a potential client that he could bring in for us. He knew the client through his father, who will be the acting representative for the client who is currently overseas in England at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we waited for the client to get back to us, Alec assigned us each a different task for the terms of reference. I will be working on our company description and design requirements for the client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/11/finding-a-client/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/11/finding-a-client/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Kreative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kreative is a small interactive design agency based in Titanic Quarter, Belfast. We are a collective of students aiming to come up with, create and realise simple, digital solutions which communicate the values and relevant messages of our clients in a wide variety of industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group consists of;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alec Devlin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Declan Magee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lauren McKimm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tajdid Rahman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/09/about-kreative/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tajdid.me.uk/projectblog/projectblog/kreative/2014/09/09/about-kreative/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kreative</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
